Finding aid to the Special Programs files CA.MS.01009
Smith College Archives
Special Programs records
1904-2014
Smith College Archives
Smith College.
CA.MS.01009
7.5 linear feet (20 containers)
The Special Programs records contain records of the Honors program, honor societies (Phi Beta Kappa), the Poetry Center, and Junior Year Abroad programs. This includes membership lists, organization records, and honors exams.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials in the Smith College Archives are open for use, with the following exceptions: "Office Files," files of records created for the use of the administrative unit that created them, are closed to research for a period of 10 years following their creation. In all cases, the College Archives will continue to provide public access to materials that were intended to be public at the time of their creation (press releases, publications, etc.)
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Unknown source
Other Finding Aids
The Phi Beta Kappa papers and some accessions have container lists that are available upon request by contacting specialcollections@smith.edu
Scope and Contents
The Special Programs records contain records of the Honors program, honor societies (Phi Beta Kappa), the Poetry Center, and Junior Year Abroad programs. This includes membership lists, organization records, and honors exams. The Phi Beta Kappa, Zeta of Massachusetts Records are thorough, encompassing publications from 1909 to 1996, correspondence from 1926 to 1993, membership lists from 1905 to 1997, and minutes from 1927 to 1963. The membership lists are expansive, detailing the education and resumes of alumnae members. There are also records of the organizations publications from 1942 to 1996.
Smith College.
- General Honors (Box 1109)
- Special Honors, A-Ge (Box 1110)
- Special Honors, Greek-Z (Box 1111)
- Examinations, A-E (Box 1112)
- Examinations, F-Z (Box 1113)
- Examinations, 1948-1959 (Box 1114)
- Examinations, 1960-1968 (Box 1115)
- Honor Societies, Phi Beta Kappa, United Chapters (Box 1116)
- Honor Societies, Phi Beta Kappa, Zeta of Massachusetts, A-K (Box 1117)
- Honor Societies, Phi Beta Kappa, Zeta of Massachusetts, M-Z (Box 1118)
- Honor Societies, Phi Beta Kappa, Zeta of Massachusetts, Alumnae Membership (Box 1119)
- Honor Societies, Phi Beta Kappa, Zeta of Massachusetts, Minutes, October 1904 - May 1927 (Box 1120)
- Honor Societies, Phi Beta Kappa, Zeta of Massachusetts, Minutes, June 1927 - June 1960 (Box 1121)
- Junior Year Abroad, A-P (Box 1131)
- Junior Year Abroad, Q-Z (Box 1131.1)
- Junior Year Abroad, France, 1927-1989 (Box 1132)
- Junior Year Abroad, Geneva, 1947-2012 (Box 1134.1)
- Junior Year Abroad, Italy, 1932-1990 (Box 1135)
- Global Studies Center- Global STRIDE projects (Box 1136)
- Jacobson Writing Center (Box 1136)
- Kahn Institute (Box 1136)
- Leadership Program (Box 1136)
- Poetry Center (Box 1136)
- Poetry Center records, 1998-2007; Accession 2018-A-0063; Poetry Center at Smith College; Ava Goga; 1.75 linear feet (1 record carton and 1 full letter doc box) (Box 1, Box 2)
  Scope and Contents
  Office files, publicity, and correspondence and photographs with poets reading at the Center
  Conditions Governing Access
  This collection is open for use without restriction beyond the standard terms and conditions of Smith College Special Collections.
  Ava Goga
- Summer Institute for Educators (Box 1137)
- Women & Financial Independence (Box 1137)
- Women in Public Service project, 2014 (Box 1137)
- Steinem Initiative (Box 1137)
- Center for the Environment, Ecological Design, and Sustainability (CEEDS)
  - CEEDS websites and social media
    The archived website, blog and social media sites for the Smith College Center for the Environment, Ecological Design, and Sustainability (CEEDS). The CEEDS archived websites were were first captured in 2018. Subsequent captures are scheduled annually. CEEDS aims to "integrate sustainable practices into Smith's operations and connect campus operations with student learning... support faculty in their efforts to deepen their understanding of salient environmental issues and to integrate those issues into the curricula... promote institutional innovation and progress toward the college's commitment to be a model of sustainability."
    - CEEDS blog, first captured Jun 27, 2018; 1 website
    - CEEDS Facebook page, first captured June 12, 2018; 1 website
    - CEEDS Twitter, first captured Jul 12, 2018; 1 website
    - "Sustainable Smith" website, captured 2018; 1 website
      Related Materials
      Subsequent captures of this website can be found in the larger Smith College web archive.
- Center for Religious and Spiritual Life
  - Center for Religious and Spiritual Life blog, first captured 2018; 1 website
    The archived blog of the Smith Center for Religious and Spiritual Life newsletter articles, updates from student orgs, op-eds about topics related to religion and spirituality, includes newsletters since 2017, and posts relating to the Center's activities, campus and world news and events related to religious and spiritual concerns.
    Accruals
    The website was first captured in 20187. Subsequent captures are scheduled annually.
    The archived website of the Smith College Center for Religious and Spiritual Life is captured as part of the larger Smith College archived website.